<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic | Sudeepa Nadeeshan</title>
    <link>/tags/academic/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Academic</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>/tags/academic/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Your Own Blog?</title>
      <link>/post/what_happend_to_previous_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/what_happend_to_previous_blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the third blog that I&amp;rsquo;m running as a computer professional. :D (Hope this will be the last one. Migrations are not that smooth). Let me briefly explain how I ended up here. First, I started a blog on Blogspot back in 2017, and It was cool. It was &lt;a href=&#34;http://sudeepanadeeshan.blogspot.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(http://sudeepanadeeshan.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;. I was not happy with the way that blog look. That time I got to know about Wordpress. So I planned to move to Wordpress, but this poor student did not have enough money (or wasn&amp;rsquo;t willing to pay pocket money to some hosting company). Obviously, I checked for free services. Finally, I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.000webhost.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;000webhosting&lt;/a&gt;. Excellent, Cpanel hosting service with a free Tier. I jumped in. Searched for hundreds of free appropriate themes and  finally satisfied with  &lt;a href=&#34;https://themehall.com/me-omega-child-theme&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Me&lt;/a&gt; from themehall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I customized the theme in for my requirement. Added tweeter handle, coding plugins, blah blah. The blog was totally fine. You can check it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20181209035942/http://sudeepanadeeshan.me&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;web.archive.org&lt;/a&gt;. Everything was fine until 000webhost suddenly decided to delete my website from there servers without keeping ANY BACKUPS! I even tried to pay for the past months and get the site back. NOTHING WORKED! Actually, I should not blame them for not keeping the backups as it is my duty to baking up my own website (but come on, you should keep something for the customers!). So that&amp;rsquo;s how I said goodbye to Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Me by Themehall&#34; title=&#34;Logo Title Text 1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wanted to develop my blog again. But I was not particularly eager  to use any blogging platforms like Medium (As I do know something about coding ;) ). I did some research about the available blogging platforms for coders and heard about &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. Hugo has several themes and widgets. I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt; theme very attractive among them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic has been released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license. George Cushen lists key features of &lt;strong&gt;Academic&lt;/strong&gt; as follows,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page builder&lt;/strong&gt; - Create &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/page-builder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;widgets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit any type of content&lt;/strong&gt; - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create content&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/jupyter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupyter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin System&lt;/strong&gt; - Fully customizable &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/themes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display Code and Math&lt;/strong&gt; - Code highlighting and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX math&lt;/a&gt; supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrations&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus commenting&lt;/a&gt;, Maps, Contact Forms, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Site&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry-Leading SEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Help get your website found on search engines and social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Galleries&lt;/strong&gt; - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Friendly&lt;/strong&gt; - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-language&lt;/strong&gt; - 15+ language packs including English, 中文, and Português&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-user&lt;/strong&gt; - Each author gets their own profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Pack&lt;/strong&gt; - Assists with GDPR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out&lt;/strong&gt; - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Click Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; - No servers. No databases. Only files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain specific intent classification system ...</title>
      <link>/project/fyp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/fyp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A neural network based intent classification system for a specific domain that has the capability to identify the intent of an uttered command in Sinhala language without converting to text. Two research papers were submitted. A mobile web app was developed for collecting voice samples.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Behaviour Analytics for Public Transportation Services</title>
      <link>/project/transport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/transport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This application was built for Natural Language Processing Centre of University of Moratuwa. The client had a very large data corpus and there were some erroneous tags for the words. A tag is basically the type of the word like abbreviation, full stop, adjectival noun, postpositions, pronouns etc (There are around 30 tags). It was required to change the tag according to the position of the word in a single sentence or change the tag of the selected word for the whole corpus. Usability and consistency were the main considerations of the application. So different methods were added to search the content like searching by word and searching by tag. The editor can be configured to and corpus with the same corpus conventions and the changes are consistently saved in the file system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
